all right guys welcome to week 2 this
week we're talking about snicker
simple non-interactive kalindra and with
keys for encryption reused I'm gonna
allow myself 15 minutes to go through
the paper like we did last week and then
we'll open it to discussion we're very
lucky that Adam Gibson the author of
this this BIP proposal is here so he's
going to answer questions and correct
what anything that I've said that might
be wrong okay so this is where you can
find more about this we're taking from
github so the link is here the
PowerPoint will be uploaded somewhere
I'll make sure that happens okay last
week just a quick reminder we did a
knapsack coin join in our summaries was
that we can mix with arbitrary values if
we do a tactical partition of outputs
breaking them down further to make more
possible interpretations of coin joy
transaction so last week was knapsack
this week is snicker next week we will
discuss at the end of this video and you
can always find out what we're doing at
the wasabi research Club link okay so
what's the problem that's being
addressed with current coin joints the
entire concept around snicker if I
understand it correctly is that we're
trying to deal with the fact that the
coin joins are interactive if you're
familiar with how wasabi or join market
or any coin joint system works you have
all these participants that need to
coordinate together typically this
coordination requires a coordinator and
even if the coordinator takes special
precautions to use you know blind
signatures and tour and all these things
there's still some amount of privacy
that's being leaked because of the
coordinator it's also very difficult to
coordinate as you know with wasabi if
you have 100 participants there can be
all sorts of issues with coordination
and the coordination is fragile to
attack because now there's a central
point of failure so if someone really
wanted to hurt a particular mixing
protocol they could just attack the
server that's during the coordination
with the denial of service attack for
example so this is the question you're
going to ask today which is could a
Quadra be done with
coordination so on the right we see it a
typical coin joined like some something
like wasabi with you
yeah these inputs you have these outputs
and you have these mixed green outputs
that could belong to any of the
participants and when you think it's
fundamentally consists of three things
that need to be allocated from every
participant which is an input and output
and signature so those three things
we're gonna address in this in this
paper so part one inputs so I'm directly
now reading from the snicker version
zero and version one so how can we
figure out an input for a coin joint
well a proposer in this scheme because
we'll have two people proposer and a
receiver they obviously know their own
input because they're the ones that's
interested in in mixing but they don't
know the input of a potential coin joint
buddy because we're not using
coordination there's no there's no
people that are waiting you know in line
to do this so one way we can deal with
this is that those are simply guesses
which you txl in the blockchain might
most likely be interested so maybe
there's 10,000 utx those that fit the
right specifications and and now this
this proposer that's trying to do an
uncoordinated conjoint it's gonna guess
which of those might be just in doing
one joint so maybe that you take so that
they they look for our ones that are
part of a joint market transaction or
that are just at random or maybe a coin
join that comes from a previous
interaction you know later on a sticker
it gets more adopted so here on our left
we have our orange you cube so we are
the proposer in this case and we're
looking at in the world and we see all
of these possible utx those that could
be our inputs and really what we're
doing is we're just essentially just
randomly selecting one that meets the
criteria which is that it's smaller than
our utx so in this case 21 so twenty
works is we're just constructing the
coin joint ourselves so if we're orange
then black is some other person this is
what it's going to look like here so
obviously we're going to match the value
with the value of the chick so we're
selecting and then we're gonna have some
change for ourselves so so far that's
what it looks like and we could continue
doing this over and over again for any
number of UTX knows we simply select aut
Excel
a pool put it on the input side create
the transaction fill everything in so
that covers inputs so with inputs we're
just going to guess with outputs
well upper filter knows their own
address and they know their own unused
addresses right so every time we create
transactions we use fresh addresses but
how will a composer figure out a fresh
address that belongs to another party
that isn't participating in the same
transaction right this is actually I
think the most interesting and clever
part of snicker so what we're going to
try to answer this question so there's
there's the question of you know when I
take this 19 you know Bitcoin and you
tick so input that I found on the
blockchain and I construct this
transaction myself what are we gonna
fill in for the address of the person
that I'm trying to there's no back and
forth this isn't coordinating so there's
an obvious solution which is just copy
the same address used by that ETF so so
that you kick so is using an address
with a public key you know X just you
reuse the same public key
well obviously that's not very smart
because that it exactly points out to
the to the public that the the unwinding
of the coin joint so that's a very
simple working solution but it's
obviously it doesn't do anything privacy
wise so there's a smart solution is that
we can use in a dress that is tweet from
the public key of the YouTube so by a
common shared secret between parties all
right so what we're gonna do is we're
going to take the public key that we
know our mystery user has which is on
the left here the the input of 19 we're
going to take that public key and we're
going to tweak it with a common shared
secret and here I think we have to take
oh wait just yeah so so all we know so
all we know about the mystery you take
so is that exists as a private key to
the public key that holds the funds but
it's important understanding this in
this model that the public key isn't
explicitly written in a uth so when you
send money to someone you only make a
commitment to the hash of their public
key
so what that means is that we can only
know a public key to an address if that
address has spent funds from it in the
past so that this is where the idea of
address reused comes in so really we're
looking for an address that has a coin
that has UTM so and an address that's
previously spent another uth so from it
and thus revealed its public key so but
how will we tweak the public key of the
receiver with a shared secret so this is
the really the the coolest part and it's
I think it's the only time we need to
take a brief aside in terms of math so
we're going to just quickly cover some
stuff that you can you can not worry
about if you don't care but the way that
elliptic curve math works is that on our
first line here we have some private key
P and its associated with the public key
P when run through the elliptic curve
with generated port G and a different
person's public key private key might be
K and it has a public key of capital K
and as it turns out you could do
addition of private keys because private
keys are just numbers and a number of
times you run through the Yale if T
curve and so this allows us to do
something really cool which is called
the diffie-hellman key exchange where we
can essentially if two people each have
a public key then they can apply their
private key against the other person's
public key to create a common shared
secret so that's pretty much the only
thing you need to know and some people
will know this is very basic of
cryptography other people will probably
not be able to appreciate it so what
we're gonna do with it
take the receiver's public heat and then
create a shared secret key home and
shared secret between the public our
public he has a proposer and their
public key and what we end up getting is
a point on the elliptic curve and I
believe that that is deadly
a hashed in the specification but the
point is that there's a shared secret
and so now the output that I'm sending
the funds to isn't to the same address
but rather the same address tweet such a
way that anyone in the outside world has
no idea that that tweet address
corresponds to the the input address
only that the the two participants know
that shared secret with each other ok so
so far we have selected a bunch of
candidate you take zoe's for the inputs
and specifically with reused addresses
then we've created a recipient address
with a divvy element week value see the
last part is what about signatures right
because we know that we have a coin
joint we need all the participants to
sign and validate that everything makes
sense so in this case what we're going
to do is the proposer is going to sign
their own input creating a PS bTW a
partial assignment transaction and there
they need to make that partially signed
Bitcoin transaction available to the
receiver and the way that you can do
this it's it's very open to two
different ideas but essentially it can
be a public message board it can be some
public server it could be directly
peer-to-peer where a participant of the
proposer is just you know sending out
these PSB T's to many many people and so
the the idea here is that you know we
have this input of 21 on the left and
we're taking all these valid utx those
that might possibly work and we're
creating all of these partially signed
Bitcoin transactions where we are
signing only our own input and then
we're essentially propagating these
partial assignment or transactions all
around so we're broadcasting them maybe
to a message board maybe to our peers
however it's done and hoping that
someone picks it up
signed off on the transaction and then
themselves broadcasts it to the network
to the Bitcoin network right so a
receiver can verify that the contents of
the PS BT and validate that the
diffie-hellman tweet public key matches
what they have the receiver can then
choose to sign or not sign there's an
important point to note that it would be
not safe to just broadcast these PS BTS
without encrypting them because a
malicious listener could essentially
track down these PS BTS and and record
them and then if any of these PSP T's
got signed they could essentially unwind
that the pointer that's happening so a
simple solution is just encrypt the PS
BT against the public key of the other
party that you're dealing with so now
all you have is these blobs of encrypted
data and essentially a single public key
that can decrypt it and very little was
revealed about about what's going on
there so in version zero the summary is
a proposer selects potential UTX those
from reused addresses your poster then
constructs outputs by tweaking the
receivers public key with a
diffie-hellman key exchange then
proposes none of the clothes are
broadcast and encrypted PS bt to a
public forum or it appears directly and
then receiver can decrypt and sign and
broadcast so some really cool things to
observe here the two takeaways of what
makes this protocol cool is a is firstly
well I would say secondly but but
firstly that sticker is a deterministic
protocol
everything is on chain and if a user is
restoring their wallet and their wallet
is snicker compatible then their wallet
should have no problem in figuring out
the tweaked public keys created from
snicker transactions so there is no need
to store pristine data this is different
than a lightning protocol where data
needs to be stored and if you don't have
that data stored somewhere
your urea your 24 words is not gonna be
able to find that data for you and the
most important thing the whole point of
the snicker protocol is that it's not
interactive so some people don't
understand what the word non-attractive
means in this case what we're saying is
that the receiver only participates the
very very last stage having had no prior
interactions with the proposer so it's
minimally interactive the minimal you
can the minimum interaction you can have
is signing a transaction and that's what
we're talking about here you know if you
compare with the wasabi protocol right
now you have many many interactions
where you have people registering their
inputs then you have people registering
you know blinded outputs and then and
then registering their change and then
back and forth and back and forth and in
this case we only have one interaction
at the very very end the proposer is
doing a lot of work for sure by
propagating a lot of transactions and by
doing a lot of figuring out in terms of
guessing addresses and public keys and
and potential UTX those but the receiver
is doing very little here so sticker
version one has a simple addition which
is how can we implement snicker without
requiring address for use that is
without requiring the receiver to reveal
their public key and this you know also
quite clever which is that well what if
the proposer could just guess the
co-ownership of a used address as in UTM
so sitting in unused addresses so as a
you know a simple way of saying that is
you know if you look over here on the
right on the right we have an output of
value 10 and that is a UT EXO that we
think is snicker compatible with us so
we're proposer we look at output 10 we
see that has a lot of potential but we
don't know the public key to that that
output but what we observed is that the
transaction where it comes from has one
input in two outputs and it looks like
output of value 10 is the change so we
can say is that input of 19 is also
change is also belong to the same owner
thus that public key probably is in that
public private key pair is
is the same person who has the
public/private key pair of the output of
10 which is still unspent so essentially
what we're doing is we're trying to not
only randomly guess a valid UTX so that
works with us but also some ancestor
that's reveal its public key that we can
then use to create the transaction so
this is what it looks like I essentially
cria on the right you know you have your
your input of 21 I select the output of
value 10
I create my coin joy transaction and the
black output 10 on the very far right
uses the public key from input 9 19 way
on the left so I'm not using the same
address but a past address because that
pass address has revealed its public key
so snicker in summary is non-interactive
coin joints are possible between two
participants by leveraging either reused
addresses or you know guessing
co-ownership and a public board for
posting PSV T's or some form of
communication and I think that is it
that's everything
so yeah Adam can jump in with Adam
Gibson can jump in with any thoughts and
open I just think you are valuable to
just quickly outline the schedule for
today so first of all Adam Adam gives on
whenever you want to leave just say so
and and leave don't feel pressured this
thing here
second I want to very first thing I want
to you guys to say questions that only
the outer can answer so we can get over
that and then we can do questions and
then we can do discussions on topics and
then we can do all new ideas this
sneaker gave us and finally discuss what
the next week's paper should be so
one one question does anyone else have a
presentation so first a beeps
presentation Adam what was what was your
impression what do you think do you want
to correct something now I I want to say
it's very clear really high quality so
congratulations on an excellent piece of
work there the I was I was looking from
steaks yeah I think there might have
been one equation in the only math slide
that was wrong but it's such a trivial
point that I won't even mention
everything else was absolutes
I mean seriously explain it very clearly
I guess you didn't explain every detail
but I think you explain most of what's
in the bit yeah and I was very good so I
think it's more case that if people here
have things coming out of that that
they'd still don't understand and and
myself and have evil anyone else can try
and explain it about the questions I
mean in general I think when I first got
to know Snickers I thought it was just
transfers but especially if we're
reading a bit now and this is especially
powerful for example with change
analysis right so if we have a user
point the same spend and the public
here's video right and most transactions
that change point will be the stuff from
the same owner than the input right so
just by having a single regular spending
transaction and then likely do you think
is it that that we can find a successful
proposal for Snickers you know if we do
change heuristics and others
yes a couple of points on that the first
point is there's a kind of ironic beauty
and this this scenario which is that
specifically in the case where there is
bad you TXO privacy management that is
the case where this is possible right
because if you know which is the change
then you know which one is right but you
can do a coin joins take a coin joint
coming out of it well that's a kind of a
quip and a joke but the more serious
point is is it just it doesn't really
matter
I mean think of it this way a typical
transaction has a spending output and a
change output and that's kind of also
somewhat true with coin joins where you
just have multiple people together and
you still have like one out and one
chain one coin joint out one change oh
and yeah if you don't know we let's say
in a typical spending transaction which
one's the spender which ones have
changed then you can just make a
proposal for both it's not a big deal I
mean you this will naturally lead on to
the more the more important practical
question of you know how do we handle
bring lots of proposals but I don't
think at first it seems like an
important question but you think about
it it kind of isn't right this is very
opportunistic yeah that's what I think
if the not recognize that they are
snicker coinsurance then they look like
so sorry yeah that's that's kind of a
different point isn't it which is
there's there's this question that I've
Eve correctly like handled in the
presentation which is like how do you
identify candidates for this process if
you're trying to kind of bootstrap or
seed the process then you might want to
be taking you might want to be proposing
coin joins on UT exo's which are not
themselves coin join UT EXO so they
could be ordinary wallets pending
transactions that's a bit tricky but if
you're going to try well alright but if
you're going to try and do it obviously
you have the fundamental issue ever know
which one is the change because I need
to know if I'm going to use sneaker
version one then
need to know which one is the change so
that I can map it to the input of the
transaction and get a public key so if
you're going to do that then you just
might have to try it twice instead of
once because a typical spending
transaction only has two outputs right
doesn't have like 100 if you don't need
about coin joint transaction and you're
taking UTX those from that then it's a
different story right but generally
speaking that's going to be somewhat
easier and then the kind of third case
is if it's if you want to build a
sneaker transaction from a previous
Snicket transaction and that again like
the coin joint case is easy because it's
very easy to analyze that transaction in
terms of which one is the change right a
few but if anyone else wants to interact
me feel free one thing I would like to
ask is how you see things going forward
with this so you know you have proposers
that are scanning the the watching
ideally you would you would have wallets
that are sneaker compliant mmm that you
know and and so they would they would
connect to this like message board or
repository of sneaker PS BTS mm-hmm
encrypted proposals yeah okay do you
want to talk a bit about incentives
because I don't know if you said
anything about that in the paper but how
do you see incentives laying out in
terms of people profiting off of these
transactions yeah I am I think I didn't
talk about it much but I did briefly
mention it I think in the future
improvements section I was just sort of
waffling a little bit about you know
under what circumstances might you be
able to do this to actually actually do
payments and anyway but forget that and
your question is obviously very relevant
incentives I think it's a it's it's a
slightly unclear point to me but I'm
hoping that it's one of those situations
where the market figures it out for you
so essentially you've got a degree of
freedom
in the proposal that you make so in your
nice presentation you clearly showed
like what the transaction looks like you
have two inputs one from each party and
you have two equal sized outputs and
then one change output for the for the
receiving party now even in that
simplest model that's the model that
exists in the proposal it obviously is
possible to to tweak like who is paying
the Bitcoin transaction fee in there and
who and maybe further at one party might
actually receive additional funds
depending on some details one party
might it might be the proposer and it
might be the receiver and I can see
arguments for both the most natural and
my suspicion is that this would start
off with a kind of proposes making
proposals which receivers do receive
money from but it could easily be
imagined as going the other way
only because proposes have more work to
do than receivers and thirdly as I was
just mentioning at the start there we
could imagine a slightly different model
of snica where somebody wants to spend
money in a coin join and actually forced
a receiver to take a specific sized
output that would require four outputs
instead of three now that's not actually
included in the BIP it's just something
I was thinking about as a future
possible improvement and the reason that
I find that fascinating because I could
imagine this scenario where like imagine
you wanted to you wanted to pay someone
one BTC and or you wanted to do it with
slightly you know better privacy but you
were willing to sort of wait a little
while but if you sweeten the pot
significantly you might find that you
know putting out 100 proposals you
immediately get one of them snapped up
and all the receivers are in a race to
get that to get that money so it could
actually create very bizarrely like fast
process even though it's totally not
interactive yeah you know Adam kind of
jumping upon this point what if we add
one round of interact so Ellis proposes
this turned back to you
involved downloading secrets and fees
but Bob actually wants to do an equal
value or like a different equal value to
pay one specific amount and then Bob
creates the second proposal adjusted to
his knee and he decrypt this to Alice's
up game publishers bag through the
bulletin business where the hell it
download it it's interesting no maybe I
mean this almost it's almost the case
that you you can't stop him right I mean
I don't actually think that there's it's
not it's almost not needed to change any
anything in the proposal for that to
happen right no no it would just be
client-side the second Shaker proposal
but you already two peers who have
already established some form of
communication before I suppose well that
that suggestion that's a very
interesting suggestion I suppose what it
throws up is the point which isn't
really clear which is to what extent are
these roles separate separated the
proposer in the receiver and to what
extent should they be separated now I
originally had in mind a quite
asymmetric scenario because I fell and I
think I'm think this is true really that
the proposal because of needing a
significant amount of sort of blockchain
scanning skills and access to the
ability to scan blockchain to find
candidates the proposes job is you know
significantly more difficult than
receiver Arabs I was specifically trying
to advertise the idea that the receiver
side of this protocol is something that
could be implemented in mobile wallets
pretty easily but I think if you try to
make the two parties symmetrical in
their abilities and you say that any
snicker enabled wallet is able to do
both sides that would be cool but I am
afraid that it imposes slightly larger
computation and etc cost and you know
development costs on unless a mobile
wallet they wanted to implement the
proposal so I'm quite keen to defend the
idea that people could be receiver only
and it could be nice and simple but that
doesn't of course aside the possibility
that like the soup top
professional-grade wallet he is able to
do both sides and is able to do what you
just said which is that you may give
even because they're constantly
listening for proposals like they
a proposal and they get get booked get
one back we're on the same mute EXO
that's that's really kind of clever I
like that thank you
well the S well it's funny when I was in
what was the Amsterdam and I was
explaining this touch to roast beef or
the shaky they said that's a backronym
isn't it I said you're absolutely right
it's very backronym you know back your
backronym means no backronym okay
backronym is just like you know acronym
is that word in English that refers to
the case where you give the initials of
something like PS BT is an acronym
starting with a so there's this kind of
joke word backronym which is where you
you think up the name and then you
choose the words to make it fit that
acronym offense so so basically I was
trying to find a memorable word for non
in what the origin of this was in
thinking about the idea of non interact
with coin join generally that there have
been various some ideas proposed in the
past and none of them quite really
worked for making coin join
non-interactive so the S is just to make
it work it's just the backronym since
the Seneca is simple but the keys for
encryption reused I think does actually
make sense right because you I mean
maybe if it wasn't a backronym it would
have been keys are used for encryption
but but it doesn't make sense right
because you either take a reused address
so you have a key a public key there
that you're reusing for encryption or
you you're taking a key from a previous
transaction and reusing it for
encryption by the way this brings up a
point that is sometimes discussed in
this Mis protocol is you know to what
extent is the encryption part necessary
I personally think it is either
completely necessary or it's very very
desirable but it's a kind of an
interesting thought experiment to
imagine how all this would work if the
PSB T's or the anyway the the signatures
on transactions were just broad cards
onto the message board in the clear it's
I think it's not really desirable so I
think the encryption part although it's
sort of a little bit extra complex it II
it's it's it's kind of necessary yeah
[Music]
because well before that thanks Adam for
joining us and my question is for
example we have this machine that the
Vasavi conjoin machine that knows the
inputs right and they change address for
for for every single participant if you
if you were working with wasabi and you
know that and you have this this thing
and what what could you do for example
could you create a proposal for every
change output or or what can how can we
take advantage of this that we already
have here to to implement sneaker easier
or more effective I don't know
sure sure I don't know one I'm kind of
hoping that you're going to explain this
to me a bit more because I remember the
the reason I wrote the draft bit was
because you had a thread on your github
and I thought all people are interested
in in the idea of doing this and I
wanted to make sure there was some kind
of clear clearly defined protocol
written somewhere so that if people like
you want to discuss hit you you at least
have something concrete to discuss now
how would the wasabi scenario how would
it change this and I don't actually know
for sure in in the naive sense okay when
we have a wasabi coin we have a large
transaction with a lot of outputs we
could try to propose a lot of who we is
in the sentence but we could try to
propose snicker coin joins on the change
outputs but to do that we would need to
use the version 1 of snicker in other
words because there's no address reuse
we would need a public key to work with
so I don't know whether you're going to
make proposals on input keys from
deposit does that make sense you don't
have the eggs pops to you or sitting
this is great it puts our are usually
quite linkable to change no it's not
always a high percent clear but in most
cases you can quickly yeah yeah yeah you
have that's true but that's not actually
addressing the point is it if you think
about it because the what you remember
in version 1 the point is you have to
find the what am I trying to say you've
got the you know yeah yeah yeah yeah
you're right yeah that's that's all you
need yeah yeah yeah it because it's a
big coin joining you can generally link
inputs to outputs that addresses the
problem yeah you're right another cool
thing was to respond the architecture
that is that the participants of the
coin join by the receipt of the coin
joint transaction as well as the blog
very swiftly so they could the those
gifts that actually communicate in the
zero link when John itself could then do
a snicker coin joint then be very
quickly afterwards you get the problem
he also for their before for their
change out but maybe even within the
same block yeah but I mean well first of
all yes I agree with everything everyone
said I was never really clear though why
you find this this interesting
specifically now wasabi said I think
it's just generally interesting for
everyone somewhat but I thought the
really obvious like best use case for
this was like a a mobile wallet that
wanted some extra privacy feature but
didn't want to have to implement a
massive
you know a big coordinated over a
network and to a server or not to a
server whatever they didn't want
something to complicate it but they just
wanted something that very positively
over a long period would add more coin
joints isn't it the case was something
like wasabi that you have you had the
guys the guys there right he's connected
up to the server and he's done is his
mixing and he's guys and on sets and
what-have-you and if he's got change
outputs that he's not happy with he can
just put it through another round of
mixing Connie or yes yes you're
absolutely right we are trying to do do
research alternatives to provide new new
privacy features and the receiver is
more or less clear to me how to do it
and it's easy to do in a mobile in a
mobile wallet yes yeah but the proposer
and it has to do more job and we can do
that I mean I think we can provide
because I mean I think for example the
electron-electron team was saying that
well they maybe could implement the the
receiver part and I think many people
who can do that because it's is probably
easier so we can we can do the proposer
I think and that could be great because
you need a proposal yeah so that that's
why and it doesn't have to do to
generate revenue for us it's just we
want to be that the best wallet just
that Brian I see what you mean yeah so
if you when you say we can be the
proposal are you saying would it be
something like the the client like
they've got desktop wallet desktop
wasabi wallet are they gonna be
effectively making like requests to -
wasabi servers to scan oh no they have
their own Bitcoin core they might have
their own Bitcoin core right however how
are they getting these scanning results
to find proposals how would that work
for running or you
you'd use the block that you already
have downloaded because we animal he's
asking he's asking where the proposals
would come from and I'm guessing the
answer is either coordinator or in
wasabi there would be like it would
point to a public you know repository
where these proposals are being
maintained
I guess the client just needs a list of
candidates this is the difficult the
thing that's kind of somewhat intensive
is to get candidate UTX oh isn't it
because once you've got a candidate you
TXO you could act as proposal and
construct a proposal pretty easily on
its it's not pretty more complicated
than the receiver is it yeah I think so
and then you just you just encrypt in
and you just put it wherever the
bulletin wasabi could also maintain a
bulletin board that would be nice and
easy for you because it's just going to
be a bunch of you know binary blobs so
it's you know so hypothetically wasabi
could be snigger compliant and then not
deal with the repose at all
but just tell everyone it's snigger
compliant and then maybe have a place
where people can post their proposals
and people should just no you should you
should only target you TXO is from you
know recent wasabi coin joints in
particular the change outputs that would
make it different proposers hmm yeah you
could restrict it I thought I would that
would that would certainly make things a
bit easier to handle yeah oh yeah yeah
thanks for reminding me I forgot about
that it's just one small detail but it's
very simple and elegant which is the if
we you know obviously these things take
time don't they but if everyone switched
a taproot then there would be no
discussion about version zero and
version one that would just be a version
two for taproot which is because the
taproot exposes the public key directly
in the utx oh then there would be no
need to make an inference or to worry
about reused addresses I actually forgot
that and David Harding's helped me after
treacherous we're in the thing
professional bodies I mean the tablet
puppy is a tweak of you right yeah you
know if it's interested twice peaked
week okay yeah I mean he's I mean it's
kind of abstract isn't if you think
about it like the taproot public key is
you know notionally tweet with the
script but but if you're just creating
just vanilla taproots egg white version
one outputs you're just that's
irrelevant because you're just going to
know the private key anyway so I mean
yeah you're right in theory that if you
know it's actually you make a fair point
because because if I go in as a proposer
and look on the blockchain and I find
all the taproot outputs I never know
which ones are actually like tweaks with
an actual script which ones are just
like a public key and and there's no
script behind it but no Merkle route you
know but you're right so in some like
abstract sense it's like a tweak of a
tweak but that doesn't change anything
maybe you should take the tweaking
factor for the original private here and
it's not never really gonna work like
that in practice is it because if if
it's an ordinary tap root output and
it's not like some weird multi city in
which cases this is never gonna work or
I don't even want to think about it then
you're you're just gonna be the person
who owns it is just gonna be signing on
the full key just like they do usually
you know because usually even in
multi-sig tap root you're signing on the
main key though the the keep are
spending because you just just override
the contract you know I'm waffling now
ignore me anyway there's no there's no
issue there's no issue it's fine yes
that that's created I didn't have that
in mind it you know if if if we
implement that route to
all the output of the our conjoint
transactions could be a candidate for
for for sneakers because it is clear
these people that wants to gain privacy
so is some is they are natural
candidates yes interesting that you look
at it like this that you think of it
more in terms of like we could be
proposes because I think the the sales
pitch I've tried to like get people to
see this is that the sales pitch of this
is the ability to have coin joints
without doing anything at all that's how
I tried to sell it to people I don't
think that the let's not forget in all
this discussion yet the huge weakness of
the idea is the it's just to party coin
joints right and so you've got to be
looking at it in a certain way like and
I think it's in a way it's almost the
opposite at the wasabi I was on a
podcast a few weeks back and I said this
is why I said it's like think of it as
like a spectrum wasabi is really on one
end and this is on the other end because
wasabi is very tightly coordinated very
tightly coupled like everyone gets
together and it's got advanced
cryptography to make sure the privacy
still works but it is tightly coupled
and it means that you know if as long as
people are willing to get together and
do it works right whereas this is
exactly the opposite this is like the
ultimate laziness of coin joint is like
I really don't give a I'm just
running a wallet and on my phone and I
switch it on every day or two that's the
thing right this system could work even
if you don't switch your wallet on very
often because it could just when you
switch it on it could download the
latest proposals for your key or by the
way we didn't mention that indexing keys
okay I'll stop waffling but I think
there is a whole area which we haven't
discussed which is like this whole issue
of how do you deal with a huge number of
proposals yeah let's talk about that
that brings together pretend and spam
issues
can you talk about well
no no I want you I want you to talk
please guys so you've had a couple of
ideas how to how to prevent prevent the
spam issue and I'm most interested in
the Hashcash swamp that's why I would
first discuss the non Hashcash ponds
so first someone could pay some money -
I don't know Baron or central
coordinator or something like that
probably burn in order to make a
proposal yeah I would have to be
essential like that so in that scenario
you've got I'm what Alisa this is what
was in my head you've got a bulletin
board server and I was I was planning to
do this but I've just never got around
to it I just as a set it up as a kind of
a proof of concept just set up a tor
hidden service and all it does is
receives encrypted blobs as proposals
and then anyone let's say with a joint
market wallet it's some code in there
that just pings that URL that that tor
hidden service URL and just downloads
anything that connected to a particular
key so you'd index it by public key just
because it's a little bit easier so the
proposal would attach in in public the
public key for that proposal which is
not privacy loss because that's all the
blockchain anyway and it's only a
proposal it's not the receiver doing it
so a receiver would just take all of it
and just maybe for maximum privacy and
then just read the proposals for his
public key in that scenario we know
there will be a particular hidden
service and they could just say well
look you can't make a proposal unless
you less so if it's a payment to a burn
address things a to make a thousand
proposals you have to or or you get one
thousand proposals per I don't know one
unit of Bitcoin sent to the burn address
and you have to sign the key it would be
a bit of a mess and more to the point it
would be a kind of sent extra
centralization factor
but it will be one way to prevent the
obvious problem that if you send
encrypted proposals there could be a
billion of them and nobody has any idea
whether they're valid or not well this
is a problem because firstly the
encrypted blobs have the corresponding
public so most people gonna have to look
through blobs that don't really know but
also why isn't the hash cash solution of
just forcing encrypted blobs to have a
unique work well I think my power is
gonna come on to that yeah so the rest
of the ideas except with the exception
of the hash cache is all about paying
some money the fidelity bonds the paying
with liking network those are all about
paying money right well the Lightning
would be paying but let's be clear about
fidelity bonds right it's not quite the
same because you don't actually pay the
money you just lock it right so you lock
the money and you sign for it and you
know it's provably locked for some
period of time so you lose the time
value of the money but you don't
actually lose the money
so it's fiddly and that would be even
probably even more complicated than it's
just a payment right well it would be
more complicated I will be inconvenient
for user for proposals to have to lock
up their money but and also then you
have to worry about the privacy
implications this is one of the problems
I have with all these proposals is when
we're trying to create a very
privity system we're not exposing like
networking for me shouldn't trying to
get better privacy for our coins but if
we didn't have to make pain without
coins we also start worrying about the
privacy of those payments and it's like
almost infinite regress because I think
now we have to coin join my my fidelity
pons and my and my payments as well as
the coin join that I'm actually coin
joining and oh god what a mess don't
really like any of those proposals but I
don't think they're necessarily wrong
they could work I mean after all
lightning has some privacy so
from which you go hashcash the idea of
Hashcash you know is that you make some
computation and you prove that you made
that computation in order to make an
action so it would not be like well an
attacker would have to get a lot of
resources or or all BOTS or something
like that in order to to attack me to
dos attack this system and and whenever
they stopped the attack the system is
back online
so so that's the idea of hash cache
which is as you you phrased it you for
phrased it in beat message or in other
systems it's sort of kind of worked
right now I just think it's an
interesting idea but I'm just mystical
about whether whether it could be
effective or I'm not sure I'm just not
sure to be honest sorry I mean I just
realize it probably wouldn't be
effective because the proposer has to
issue so many of these proposals so if
you talk about if you if you toggle it
so that every proposal costs you know
five seconds of computation then it's
it's it's probably gonna hurt people who
are legitimate it is but but think of it
this way right in the original proposal
of Hashcash for for junk mail the
scenario there is that the attacker
wants to make yeah so in that case the
attacker probably wants to send tens of
thousands of emails and maybe has a 1%
or 0.1% conversion rate so it's quite
heavily skewed in favor or the honest
participant because an honest email user
doesn't need to send thousands of emails
maybe just a few right so that's why I
hash cash makes sense now here we've got
a kind of gray area that I don't really
know the truth of like what is the ratio
like if your attacker first of all why
are you even attacking the system
there's no monetary incentive in
attacking it so it must be like a kind
of a somebody wants to kill the system
so since we can't really measure their
economic incentive I mean how how much
what was the scaling factor that we need
to create to make it to make it feasible
for the honest user but infeasible for
the attacker and also a lot of that
equation is how many proposals do you
need to make as a proposal you need to
make tens of thousands you need to make
you need ten I have no idea it's really
it's really all up in here when you so
you know a proposal most most likely to
several proposals
especially when the coins that he
proposes for are being spent right
because and then what might be possible
is that the if they're if these
proposals are encrypted that the
proposer can prove that the encrypted
law was from a now spent output and if
he can provide the proof that this
encrypted message is no longer needed
then he has the right to add a new
accepted law or maybe three two of them
to enforce the next two thing and this
needs to come up to lead you can upload
the next you know I thought about this
and also I remember maybe it was Mac
Corallo or somebody he thought about
this and suggesting like zero and all
its proofs of certain properties of the
encrypted data I don't actually think it
works at all all right the reason I say
that is because fundamentally you can't
know for a proposal is is valid unless
you have like full consensus access to
Bitcoin because if I'm an attacker and
all I want to do is create a fake
proposal then it may be even as simple
as just like tweaking one tiny like one
byte in the UT XO input string you know
the like the 32 byte you TXO input and I
don't think that there's a way that zero
knowledge proof scan actually address
that I mean let's complete Lee putting
aside the problem that you've got of
char to proving proving properties of of
data undershot to is already very
complicated but even that wouldn't be
enough you you you need I don't know I
think it doesn't work that's what I'm
saying
I have an idea because there can be more
than just one bulletin board so we for
example in wasabi in our coordinator we
can we could have one and search for
candidates yes for example with that
because it's simpler and post proposals
to our own bulletin board where nobody
else have access to the right to post
proposals so in that in that case we
don't need any any mika-nee isn't forest
bomb protection or anything like that
because we are the only ones that post
proposals there
well mobile while it can can query our
our bulletin boards for example and
others too
so I think in our case we could do
something like that it could be very
simple yeah I think that's one of the
first like I listed four or five ways
you could try and handle this one way is
you could just restrict access
fundamentally just though it's a fixed
set of people who could make proposals
but obviously that's that's a less
interesting proposal at scale because we
want proposals from you know various
parties we don't really want wait yes oh
sorry yeah but you know we can have for
example our own bulletin board and other
people can have all all another one and
there can be just one that synchronized
that consolidate all the the proposals
in one being main or central repository
it could be I don't know I mean how can
scale that is please I think probably I
I don't know really probably is a
different problem probably it's not but
it yeah I think it can definitely work
it's just a question of how how far we
can go in making it as kind of as
effective and and broad as possible to
end point mm-hmm yeah what what's the
largest problem of pay to end point or
rather what do I think is the largest
problem of pay to end point is that it
disrupts the existing user workflow what
can we do about it what do we want we
want someone to give me an address and
then I could even send money to that
address or based on that address I could
establish peer-to-peer encrypted
communication between the someone who is
giving me the address right if we could
solve this that would be great comment
just about that you know and it all
provides what is called something like a
hiding services of something like that
that can be created on the fly
I mean without a tour config file so you
can open for example what hobby and
create an unpublished an endpoint as
hiding services as a hiding service
without any configuration file or
anything like that so you just need to
to know the the onion address of the of
your peer and that's what's important
and it turns out it's the exact same
issue that sneaker has is that how do
you send an encrypted message to someone
based on only the Bitcoin address right
you can't do that you can't get the
public key out of the Bitcoin address
unless it's a top root output now you
can create an encrypted message from the
Bitcoin address that someone sent to you
and that message would include your tour
endpoint and you could broadcast that to
appear to peer network and they would
get in communication with you so the
problem is solved what's the only
problem left is the spam attack and how
could we I didn't dare to say solve the
spam attack but definitely improve a lot
on it with hash cash that's
straightforward application to that so
what do you think about that so you say
you're basically saying bit message was
the answer all along we basically is a
peer-to-peer messaging network this
encrypted and has hash cash so you
should have stuck with me we should have
stuck with bit message
you don't want to ruin the user workflow
right it wouldn't ruin anything because
someone would give you an address and if
if the if there is no answer to to your
encrypted message then you just send the
money so the user write anything that
hey pay to end point transaction
happened the user would have no idea
about that it just gives you an address
and send your transaction and you know
but wait are you saying that as far as
you're concerned this problem is solved
by hashcash is that we using the
encrypting message problem is solved by
top route and yes issue I wouldn't dare
to say solve but even definitely
improved with head hashcash or at least
a try it worth a try you know but I
think I mean but I think the reason the
Hashcash made sense with bit message was
because bit message was like email where
were all you were trying to do is
prevent yeah no it's almost the same but
it's not quite the same
somehow oh you were trying to do is
prevent many messages many fake messages
to go out to the network yeah but yeah
not sure if it works that way right
because there are millions of other
reason attacker can figure out to get
that much computation
what's the what's what's good in it for
that occur and not really because the
transaction is still happening but yes I
think that's actually quite a strong
argument and a limited time frame that
well if if there is a if you don't find
if Nova replies to your encrypted
message within 10 seconds maybe means
how long a user can tolerate or maybe
that's that's too much already but if
you don't find an encrypted
if you don't find a communication then
you just send a normality I think for
payments where people can't tolerate a
10-second wait and then they should they
should be using lightning anyway it
would be a smaller payment generally a
retail payment now I think we've covered
a lot one thing that I was so curious is
about how to best and privately retrieve
proposals from a receiver and I thought
because we get more maybe there are
already the public keys exposed by
together with the encrypted data so I
thought it would go on rice filters
similar to block filters at the point 58
would that make sense here I'm if you're
asked to give me I'm actually not I
haven't really studied that area yet but
intuitively from like a vague idea of
what it's doing it should be the same
problem so I said I suspect a similar
solution will apply yes I mean obviously
the naive thing to do is is to download
everything that way it's like it's like
running a Bitcoin core nowhere you just
download everything and obviously the
equally naive in the other direction is
just to only take the data for your
public key which would reveal something
about you even though you know tor blah
blah blah but it would reveal something
so yeah they're kind of probably the
smart way is to have some kind of filter
that would intelligently download data
in such a way that people couldn't
because it would be a bit like Bitcoin
blocks right cuz you'd imagine you had a
mobile phone wallet you turn it on it
lets say turn on every morning for
whatever is probably so you do then
you'd want to download the data since
the previous time you logged on which
would be a chunk of encrypted proposals
and like you say we probably would want
some kind of filter to be to be as smart
about it
just a statement that I could sound
controversial but but I will ask so I
think the most efficient way working on
snicker should be actually after top
route gets on the Bitcoin network so
before that it's kind of a heck enough
their top route gets there it's it's a
more cleaner solution anyone has
anything to add to that okay the next
thing is this this is kind of silly too
because I know the answer but I I just
wanted want to ask it that you notion or
signature aggregation which results in
in in aggregating the signatures is a
notoriously interactive process why
snicker is and not obviously non
interactive process so well yeah but the
if it but the thing about Schnoor
signature aggregation is is there's
different like what's the word at
different scenarios where you use it
right if we're talking about multi-sig
then we're talking about music and that
is a three-round interactive protocol as
currently set up but that wouldn't I
mean that doesn't really apply to this
because this is this is like coin join
between different parties but if we were
talking about signature aggregation
cross inputs then as far as I know
there's there isn't even the proposal
for that yet if I remember right so so
I'm not sure what I could say about it
but I if I suppose we could imagine a
future where that was happening and
we're therefore there would be a problem
in doing this kind of protocol because
the signature but the thing is if the
signature aggregation cross inputs
requires interactivity that would at
that that statement only really
flies when more than one input is
whether when the inputs are not all
owned by the same party so only applies
to coin join and so it might mean that
you couldn't make a snicker coin join
that like other coin joins had the nice
property of reducing the size of the
transaction and therefore being more
economical so it might make snicker a
lot less attractive I guess that's what
you were had in mind is if you actually
assume interactivity then you can assume
that every wallet will implement the
signature aggregation and if snicker
wouldn't implement it then it would just
mean that's a sneaker transaction
because that you would market now it's
just different yeah but but doesn't
matter because as you said it applies if
so if you pass around the transaction
between participants it's not a problem
it's a problem when you just want to
pass back the signature to the server no
because you have to pass around the
signature the participant is not a
problem
anyway that was for me or and go ahead
guys anyone has anything asked discuss
I guess I'll say something maybe
controversial around controversial I
don't see snicker being useful outside
of the mobile devices like what that I'm
saying I'm trying to wrap my head around
different weight use cases but it was
like it's really for the mobile devices
hmm I mean maybe the only I tend to
agree but maybe the counter-argument
might be especially if what sabe uses
because I'm thinking about what sabe
specifically because because where we
are maybe for sabe user saw a value in
having this is kind of opposite to what
Lucas was saying because I almost think
like the Wasabi's uses what might want
to do it between themselves and not
involve the wasabi server at all
because I think what sabe model is
pretty strong but the there is a
theoretical weakness of you know the
server maybe sort of sibling and stuff
like that maybe that's silly I don't
know but but I just think maybe you
could imagine what's up because of a
sabi coin joint like a joy market coin
each one has the property of being a
very stick but certain things have
happened you might find it useful to
sort of do extra coin joins pulling off
the edge although that may be the small
good example there's also something
about small coin joints that's very
unappealing which is that they're very
inefficient might provide it's always
better to have as many people as
possible
so yeah it's sometimes easy to forget
this in 2020 or whatever says good feast
so Chetan her taste but only couples ago
it was just a bit of a nightmare doing
questions it's a good point oh you know
if I would have read that Mesabi is
probably a bit too heavy software to do
the receiving of this as I said earlier
it might really be a good opportunity
for wasabi point be able to propose
makers transactions and then that then
other wallets like mobile wallet in
doing these rounds are based on wasabi
users proposing them so so that might
actually be quite interesting how we
actually contribute holding yeah you
have a selling point there don't you
because if I as a receiver get a
proposal from a wasabi output then I can
inherit partially some of the anonymity
set some of it yeah but actually a great
point that I didn't to think about here
it'll depend on the details but it could
be a thing all right any more topics or
someone or we should move on to the to
deciding what should be the next maybe
atom specifically for how do you want to
do this with a joint market we have many
and fermentation ideas with difficult oh
yeah so um well it's a bit it's been
stuck because I I wrote a PR for it for
just only the receiver side about three
four months ago a bunch of other stuff
going in the way and then I realized
that I didn't really have a good p SBT
library yeah I could use but that was
just me what what I really want to do
was I wanted to write the receiver side
into the into the join market software
and then set up a test server for a
bulletin board and then obviously they
have to would have to make proposals uh
but it would just be like me or like one
or two people making proposals initially
just to try out you know because because
I'm more interested in just like having
it get getting it tried out at this
point after having released the proposal
is written now so it's there's some kind
of like standardized format for it the
the once that's decided then I was
hoping there would be a proof-of-concept
but I haven't
really finished so you know you know how
it goes no just my opinion is you know a
max for example is a big fan of atomic
swaps and I think for example that it
sneakers is it is probably easier for
for us and it is it could be good if we
can do something because we have this
wallet that we have a server we can find
panda date on our server yes and we can
have do the the hard work so ok
but anyway it's just another another
opinion I think it it could be it could
be possible we I mean we have the
infrastructure to we can have our
bulletin board I like it that could
could be more more easier or more
flexible to implement just being a co
enjoying taker in every transaction paid
to end point so you would implement tor
communication between between people and
that would have a lot in in in in
salaries giving hot salaries to be it's
like it's like could you give me an
address yes it is you know whatever so
but but anyway my point is that the very
first issue that but obvious EDD is that
two of two Cohen joins are really
inefficient so the point
don't think okay
so ideas for next week I'm gonna
politely ask recommend something which
is the I think it's quite awful or Cache
shuffle the reason why I'm so motivated
to learn read about that is because
apparently bitcoin convict when cash
wallah it's going to implement it for
their mobile devices and so it's already
in production or very close to
production so I'd really like to
investigate that I've read the coin
shuffle and cash and coins offer plus
plus papers and they are very I don't
disagree I just want to say that if we
go with which cash offers and let's just
start with cash of paper not cash of A
plus plus not values of talking so let's
start with the coin shepherd paper and
then go one by one on the things okay so
going shuffle one idea another idea you
know for me shuffle is is also something
that we have to take a look I've read
the finish of Alencon shuffle plus blast
papers are very interesting but the de
Paris I think we will never implement
and something like that so I don't know
if it yes it is good to know more but I
don't know if if we will gain some by
snicker that I think we will never
implement it but it just brought me to
insights about top route and hashcash
that I value a lot you know and we did
not really start to work on the new
mixing we just trying to learn more
because there is a lot to learn you know
I have ideas I have a couple of things I
just I just see them one is Co enjoying
pseudo coo be cheese which is analyzing
coin during transactions it was actually
analyzing blockchain for transactions
that's that's interesting
another one is bullet boatsman from you
guys might know what's mana from from
laurent at some right that i think
that's the interesting thing to take a
look at another thing is Kanab sock code
because the guy just gave us a code base
that would be really interesting to look
into another thing is yes
cash Fusion published a paper not not
the whole cash fusion I don't propose
that that that's that's a lot but
published the paper about analyzing cash
fusion transactions it's not a paper
it's a blog post and I think that would
be really interesting in in light of
that we know now how can a buck was
analyzing the the transaction saw the
knapsack paper was analyzing the
transaction so I think that blog post
would be really interesting so let's do
the word who is voting for coin shuffle
okay I'm voting for French - yeah me too
me too me too wait just one one one more
point sorry for and next time instead of
Concha for a splash for example we can
go directly to the dining cryptographers
a problem and the DC networks instead of
jumping directly to the to the Concha
four plus plus because East is not so
easy to catch the first okay so we have
four votes to Queen suffer and die
dining cryptographer DC net listener
networks who is voting for that III vote
one yes Lucas of course no but now for
the next one the next was only conscious
probably yes all right
so Quinn join sudo cool
I vote one you can vote for multiple
things by the way sorry okay
Boyd's mom I vote one yeah would be cool
yes I vote for that to me more knock
code I
and the last one is the cash fusion
analysis amount analysis is very similar
to an Austrian sorry I didn't hear it
can you repeat it max you're voting to
this okay that's two words looks like no
one else is voting so we have Corey
shuffle and portsmen with four modes how
should we decide on that Mouse on a
blockchain
what are you ready Adam
was it me I died I know I don't I think
yes just a huge amount of stuff you know
no I don't really know Allah let you you
figure out all right so okay let's do
this oh but we do the coin shuffle but
that means for the next five weeks we
are fool because Queen shaffer DC net
surplus plus values of a cash offer cash
user I don't know oh I have more if Adam
one day can help us again it could be
great to do
to have a something about feathers and
commitments ring situation transaction
to do coin shuffle plus plus he also
need to learn how to factorize
polynomials over finite fields so
that'll be a nice session as well yeah
[Music]
oh sorry you asking me yeah that that
was sounds great um yeah that was I was
very useful actually hmm
I liked the presentation alright thank
you guys thank you very much for joining
us what was very very helpful and
insightful yes
[Laughter]